<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Moscow</string>

    <!-- Interface -->
    <string name="back_button">Back</string>
    <string name="category_list">Category list</string>
    <string name="place_list">Place list</string>
    <string name="place">Place</string>
    <string name="description">Description</string>

    <!-- Categories -->
    <string name="historical">HISTORICAL</string>
    <string name="restaurants">RESTAURANTS</string>
    <string name="interesting">INTERESTING</string>
    <string name="all">SEE ALL</string>

    <!-- Places -->
    <string name="place_name_kremlin">The Kremlin</string>
    <string name="place_address_kremlin">Moscow, Ivanovskaya Square</string>
    <string name="place_description_kremlin">The Kremlin, located in the heart of Moscow, is one of the most important and recognizable landmarks in Russia. This vast fortified complex serves as the official residence of the President of Russia and has been the center of political power for centuries. Its high walls, iconic red stars, and majestic towers make it a symbol of Russian authority and history.\n\nThe Kremlin\'s origins date back to the 12th century, but much of its current structure was built in the late 15th century under the rule of Ivan III, with the help of Italian architects. Inside the walls are several significant buildings, including the Grand Kremlin Palace, the Armory Chamber, and a collection of cathedrals. The Kremlin has seen coronations, political upheavals, and countless historical events, reflecting Russia\'s long and turbulent history.\n\nToday, the Kremlin is not only a political center but also a UNESCO World Heritage site, attracting millions of visitors each year. Its impressive architecture and deep historical significance make it a must-see destination for anyone visiting Moscow.</string>

    <string name="place_name_gum">GUM</string>
    <string name="place_address_gum">Moscow, 3 Red Square</string>
    <string name="place_description_gum">GUM, located on Red Square in Moscow, is one of Russia\'s most famous shopping centers. Built in 1893 by architect Alexander Pomerantsev with a glass roof designed by engineer Vladimir Shukhov, it blends medieval Russian style with modern industrial elements. The building\'s grand structure and intricate design make it a prominent architectural landmark.\n\nThroughout its history, GUM has been more than a shopping mall. During the Soviet era, it housed government offices and later served as a place for Soviet citizens to purchase scarce goods. Today, GUM is a luxury shopping destination, combining modern retail with historical charm, and remains a key cultural and architectural symbol in Moscow.</string>

    <string name="place_name_tretyakov_gallery">The Tretyakov Gallery</string>
    <string name="place_address_tretyakov_gallery">Moscow, 10 Lavrushinsky Lane</string>
    <string name="place_description_tretyakov_gallery">The Tretyakov Gallery is one of the most renowned art museums in Russia, housing the world\'s largest collection of Russian fine art. Founded in 1856 by Pavel Tretyakov, a wealthy Moscow merchant and passionate art collector, the gallery originally started as his private collection. In 1892, Tretyakov donated his vast collection to the city of Moscow, laying the foundation for what is now one of the most important cultural institutions in the country.\n\nThe gallery\'s collection spans centuries of Russian art, from medieval religious icons to works by the great masters of the 19th and 20th centuries, including artists such as Ilya Repin, Ivan Aivazovsky, and Viktor Vasnetsov. The Tretyakov Gallery is particularly famous for its stunning display of Russian Realism and Symbolism, offering visitors a deep insight into the country\'s artistic heritage.\n\nToday, the Tretyakov Gallery has expanded into multiple buildings, with its main branch located in the historical Lavrushinsky Lane in Moscow. It remains a cultural gem and a must-visit for art lovers seeking to explore the rich artistic traditions of Russia.</string>

    <string name="place_name_red_square">Red Square</string>
    <string name="place_address_red_square">Moscow, Red Square</string>
    <string name="place_description_red_square">Red Square is the heart of Moscow and one of the most famous public squares in the world. Its name, derived from the old Russian word "krasny," meaning "beautiful," reflects its central role in Russian history and culture. Surrounded by iconic landmarks like the Kremlin, St. Basil\'s Cathedral, and GUM, Red Square has been the stage for countless historic events, including coronations, military parades, and revolutionary moments.\n\nOriginally a marketplace in the 15th century, Red Square became a symbol of Russian statehood and power over the centuries. It was a place where czars made public appearances and, later, where Soviet leaders addressed the masses. The square\'s cobblestone pavement, coupled with its impressive architecture, offers a striking mix of historical grandeur and political significance.\n\nToday, Red Square remains a major cultural and tourist destination, attracting millions of visitors each year. Its deep historical roots and central location make it one of Moscow\'s most significant landmarks, representing the cultural and political heart of Russia.</string>

    <string name="place_name_pushkin_state_museum_of_fine_arts">The Pushkin State Museum of Fine Arts</string>
    <string name="place_address_pushkin_state_museum_of_fine_arts">Moscow, 12 Volkhonka Street</string>
    <string name="place_description_pushkin_state_museum_of_fine_arts">The Pushkin State Museum of Fine Arts is one of Moscow\'s most important cultural institutions, renowned for its vast collection of European and world art. Founded in 1912, the museum was originally designed as an educational resource for students, but over the years, it grew into a major art museum. It was named in honor of the famous Russian poet Alexander Pushkin, though it is primarily known for its art collection rather than literary heritage.\n\nThe museum\'s holdings include works from ancient civilizations, the Renaissance, and notable European artists such as Rembrandt, Rubens, and Monet. It is especially famous for its collection of Impressionist and Post-Impressionist paintings, which is one of the best outside France. The museum also frequently hosts international exhibitions, making it a hub for both Russian and global art lovers.\n\nToday, the Pushkin Museum is a key destination for those seeking to explore art from different eras and cultures. Its central location in Moscow and its world-class collection make it a must-visit for both locals and tourists.</string>

    <string name="place_name_cathedral_of_christ_the_saviour">Cathedral of Christ the Saviour</string>
    <string name="place_address_cathedral_of_christ_the_saviour">Moscow, 15 Volkhonka Street</string>
    <string name="place_description_cathedral_of_christ_the_saviour">The Cathedral of Christ the Saviour is the largest Orthodox Christian church in Russia and one of Moscow\'s most prominent landmarks. Located near the Kremlin, the current building is a reconstruction of the original cathedral, which was completed in 1883 but tragically destroyed in 1931 during Stalin\'s rule. It was rebuilt in the 1990s, symbolizing the resurgence of religion and national identity after the Soviet era.\n\nThe original cathedral was commissioned in 1812 to celebrate Russia\'s victory over Napoleon, and it took several decades to complete. After its destruction, the site was planned for a Soviet Palace, but the project was abandoned, and the area remained a public swimming pool for years. The modern reconstruction closely mirrors the original design, with its stunning white stone walls, gilded domes, and richly decorated interior.\n\nToday, the Cathedral of Christ the Saviour serves as an active place of worship and a symbol of Russia\'s religious and historical revival. Its grandeur and historical significance make it a key destination for visitors to Moscow.</string>

    <string name="place_name_bolshoi_theatre">Bolshoi Theatre</string>
    <string name="place_address_bolshoi_theatre">Moscow, 1 Theatre Square</string>
    <string name="place_description_bolshoi_theatre">The Bolshoi Theatre is one of the most prestigious and historic theaters in the world, renowned for its ballet and opera performances. Located in the center of Moscow, the Bolshoi was founded in 1776 and has since become a symbol of Russian cultural excellence. Its neoclassical façade, crowned with the iconic sculpture of Apollo\'s chariot, is one of the city\'s most recognizable landmarks.\n\nThroughout its long history, the Bolshoi has hosted countless premieres and performances by some of the greatest artists in ballet and opera. It played a central role in the development of Russian ballet, becoming home to masterpieces such as "Swan Lake" and "The Nutcracker." The theater has undergone several renovations, with the most recent restoration completed in 2011, bringing the historic building back to its former glory while upgrading it with modern facilities.\n\nToday, the Bolshoi Theatre continues to attract international audiences with its world-class productions. It remains a cultural treasure, embodying the grandeur of Russian performing arts and its rich artistic legacy.</string>

    <string name="place_name_vdnkh">VDNKh</string>
    <string name="place_address_vdnkh">Moscow, 119 Mira Avenue</string>
    <string name="place_description_vdnkh">VDNKh, also known as the Exhibition of Achievements of National Economy, is a large exhibition center and park in Moscow. Established in 1939, VDNKh was initially created to showcase the achievements of Soviet industry and agriculture. The site features a vast array of pavilions, fountains, and monumental sculptures, reflecting the grandeur and ambition of Soviet-era architecture.\n\nThe central attraction is the "Space Obelisk" and the "Friendship of Nations" fountain, which exemplify the Soviet Union\'s pride in its scientific and industrial achievements. The main pavilion, with its grandiose architecture and decorative elements, was designed to impress both Soviet citizens and international visitors.\n\nToday, VDNKh functions as a major cultural and recreational complex, hosting exhibitions, fairs, and festivals. It has undergone significant modernization while preserving its historical elements, making it a popular destination for both tourists and locals to explore the legacy of Soviet times and enjoy a variety of contemporary activities.</string>



    <string name="place_name_central_market">Central Market</string>
    <string name="place_address_central_market">Moscow, 1 Rozhdestvensky Boulevard</string>
    <string name="place_description_central_market">The Central Market, known locally as Tsentr Market, is a bustling food court and marketplace located in Moscow. It provides a diverse range of culinary options and is celebrated for its vibrant atmosphere and high-quality offerings. The market is designed to bring together various food vendors, showcasing a rich selection of local and international cuisines.\n\nVisitors to the Central Market can enjoy everything from gourmet street food to traditional Russian dishes, with a variety of options catering to different tastes and dietary preferences. The market\'s design combines modern aesthetics with a lively, communal vibe, making it a popular spot for both casual dining and social gatherings.\n\nAs a contemporary food destination, the Central Market reflects Moscow\'s growing appreciation for diverse and high-quality food experiences, offering an engaging environment for food enthusiasts and those looking to explore the city\'s culinary landscape.</string>

    <string name="place_name_cafe_at_the_garage_museum">Cafe at the Garage Museum</string>
    <string name="place_address_cafe_at_the_garage_museum">Moscow, 9 Krymsky Val Street, building 32</string>
    <string name="place_description_cafe_at_the_garage_museum">The cafe at the Garage Museum of Contemporary Art in Moscow offers a unique and stylish dining experience, reflecting the museum\'s modern and innovative spirit. Located within the museum\'s premises in Gorky Park, the cafe provides a contemporary menu featuring a selection of seasonal dishes, light meals, and beverages, often with a focus on fresh, local ingredients.\n\nDesigned to complement the museum\'s avant-garde architecture and dynamic exhibitions, the cafe\'s interior is chic and minimalist, creating a relaxed environment where visitors can enjoy a meal or coffee break. It serves as a social space for both art enthusiasts and locals, making it an integral part of the Garage Museum\'s cultural and social scene.\n\nThe cafe not only enhances the museum experience but also contributes to the vibrant atmosphere of Gorky Park, offering a refreshing spot to unwind and reflect on the contemporary art showcased at the Garage.</string>

    <string name="place_name_kofemania">Kofemania</string>
    <string name="place_address_kofemania">Moscow, 1st Krasnogvardeysky passage, 22, building 1</string>
    <string name="place_description_kofemania">Kofemania is a popular chain of coffeehouses in Moscow, known for its high-quality coffee and stylish, comfortable ambiance. Established in 2002, Kofemania has become a prominent name in the Moscow café scene, offering a refined coffee experience alongside a diverse menu of pastries, sandwiches, and desserts.\n\nThe chain is recognized for its emphasis on sourcing premium coffee beans and expertly crafted beverages, including a variety of espresso-based drinks, pour-overs, and specialty blends. Kofemania\'s interiors are typically modern and inviting, designed to provide a relaxing atmosphere for both casual meetings and solitary coffee moments.\n\nWith numerous locations across Moscow, Kofemania has established itself as a favorite spot for coffee lovers seeking a sophisticated and enjoyable café experience. Its commitment to quality and customer service has made it a staple in the city\'s vibrant coffee culture.</string>

    <string name="place_name_briquette_market">Briquette market</string>
    <string name="place_address_briquette_market">Moscow, 15 Tsvetnoy Boulevard, building 1</string>
    <string name="place_description_briquette_market">Briquet Market is a contemporary food court located in Moscow. Housed in a historic building, the market combines elements of modern design with a nod to its industrial past. Opened in recent years, Briquet Market offers a diverse range of dining options, from gourmet street food and local specialties to international cuisine.\n\nThe market is known for its vibrant atmosphere, featuring an array of food stalls and eateries that cater to various tastes and preferences. It also hosts cultural events, pop-up shops, and artisanal vendors, making it a dynamic venue for both dining and cultural exploration.\n\nWith its stylish interior and eclectic food offerings, Briquet Market has become a popular destination for food lovers and visitors looking to experience Moscow\'s culinary scene in a relaxed and trendy setting.</string>

    <string name="place_name_khlebzavod">Khlebzavod</string>
    <string name="place_address_khlebzavod">Moscow, 1 Novodmitrovskaya street</string>
    <string name="place_description_khlebzavod">Khlebzavod is a dynamic cultural and creative space located in Moscow, housed in a repurposed bread factory. Established in the early 2010s, this unique venue combines elements of art, design, and gastronomy, reflecting Moscow\'s evolving cultural landscape. The name "Khlebzavod," meaning "Bread Factory," pays homage to the building\'s industrial past.\n\nThe space hosts a variety of events, including art exhibitions, design fairs, and creative workshops. It also features a range of dining options, from trendy cafes to gourmet restaurants, providing visitors with a vibrant and eclectic culinary experience. The industrial-chic architecture of Khlebzavod, with its exposed brick and open spaces, creates an inviting atmosphere that blends historical character with contemporary style.\n\nKhlebzavod has become a popular destination for both locals and tourists seeking to explore Moscow\'s creative scene, offering a unique fusion of culture, cuisine, and community.</string>



    <string name="place_name_aptekarski_ogorod">Aptekarski Ogorod</string>
    <string name="place_address_aptekarski_ogorod">Moscow, 26 Mira Avenue, building 1</string>
    <string name="place_description_aptekarski_ogorod">Aptekarski Ogorod, or the Apothecary Garden, is a historic botanical garden located in Moscow. Founded in 1706 by Peter the Great as a medicinal herb garden, it was initially intended to support the development of pharmacy and medicine in Russia. Today, it serves as both a beautiful park and an important center for botanical research.\n\nThe garden features an extensive collection of plants from around the world, including medicinal herbs, rare and endangered species, and a variety of themed gardens. Notable areas include the Alpine Garden, the Japanese Garden, and the Greenhouse complex, which houses tropical and subtropical plants.\n\nAptekarski Ogorod offers a serene environment for visitors to explore nature and learn about plant species. Its historical significance, combined with its role as a living museum of botany, makes it a cherished cultural and educational destination in Moscow.</string>

    <string name="place_name_rooftop_at_moscow_city">Rooftop at Moscow City</string>
    <string name="place_address_rooftop_at_moscow_city">Moscow, 12 Presnenskaya embankment</string>
    <string name="place_description_rooftop_at_moscow_city">The rooftop observation decks in Moscow City offer visitors an unparalleled panoramic view of the city\'s skyline. Situated atop the towering skyscrapers of this modern business district, these observation platforms provide a stunning perspective of Moscow\'s architectural landmarks, including the Kremlin, the Moscow River, and surrounding neighborhoods.\n\nWhile there may be light dining options available, the rooftop spaces are primarily focused on offering a scenic experience rather than a restaurant-focused environment. The atmosphere is ideal for those looking to admire the city from a height, especially during sunset or nighttime, when Moscow\'s lights create a breathtaking vista.\n\nThese observation decks have become a popular destination for tourists and locals alike, providing a unique way to experience the grandeur of the Russian capital from a bird\'s-eye view.</string>

    <string name="place_name_dizayn_zavod">Dizayn Zavod</string>
    <string name="place_address_dizayn_zavod">Moscow, 36 Bolshaya Novodmitrovskaya Street</string>
    <string name="place_description_dizayn_zavod">Design Factory, located near Khlebzavod in Moscow, is a vibrant cultural and creative space known for its focus on design and innovation. This contemporary venue occupies a repurposed industrial building, maintaining the building\'s original character while transforming it into a hub for artistic and design activities.\n\nThe Design Factory hosts a variety of events, including design exhibitions, creative workshops, and art fairs. It features spaces for both established and emerging designers to showcase their work, as well as areas for collaborative projects and creative networking. The venue is also home to several design studios, galleries, and shops, offering a dynamic environment for exploring the latest trends in design and creativity.\n\nWith its emphasis on contemporary design and its role in fostering a creative community, the Design Factory has become a key destination for those interested in the intersection of art, design, and innovation in Moscow.</string>

    <string name="place_name_artplay">ArtPlay</string>
    <string name="place_address_artplay">Moscow, 10 Nizhnyaya Syromyatnicheskaya Street</string>
    <string name="place_description_artplay">ArtPlay is a dynamic creative hub located in Moscow, renowned for its focus on contemporary art, design, and innovation. Situated in a repurposed industrial complex, ArtPlay has transformed the space into a vibrant center for artistic and cultural activities. The complex features a range of studios, galleries, showrooms, and event spaces.\n\nArtPlay hosts a variety of events, including art exhibitions, design fairs, fashion shows, and workshops. It serves as a platform for both established and emerging artists and designers, offering a space for experimentation and collaboration. The venue is also known for its stylish cafes and shops, contributing to its role as a cultural destination and community space.\n\nWith its emphasis on modern art and design, ArtPlay attracts a diverse audience and has become a significant part of Moscow\'s creative scene, providing a unique environment for exploring contemporary artistic trends and innovations.</string>

    <string name="place_name_vinzavod">Vinzavod</string>
    <string name="place_address_vinzavod">Moscow, 4th Syromyatnichesky Lane, 1/8 building 6</string>
    <string name="place_description_vinzavod">Vinzavod is a prominent contemporary art center in Moscow, housed in a historic former winery. Established in 2007, it has become a key venue for modern art and cultural activities in the city. The name "Vinzavod," which translates to "Wine Factory," reflects the building\'s industrial past, which has been preserved and adapted for contemporary use.\n\nThe complex features a range of exhibition spaces, including galleries, art studios, and creative workshops. Vinzavod hosts a variety of events, including art exhibitions, design fairs, and cultural festivals, showcasing the work of both established and emerging artists. It also includes spaces for performance art, film screenings, and educational programs.\n\nWith its blend of historical architecture and modern artistic expression, Vinzavod offers a unique environment for exploring contemporary art and culture in Moscow. Its role as a cultural hub makes it a vital part of the city\'s creative community.</string>

    <string name="place_name_new_tretyakov_gallery">New Tretyakov Gallery</string>
    <string name="place_address_new_tretyakov_gallery">Moscow, 10 Krymsky Val Street</string>
    <string name="place_description_new_tretyakov_gallery">The New Tretyakov Gallery, officially known as the State Tretyakov Gallery on Krymsky Val, is an essential branch of Moscow\'s renowned Tretyakov Gallery. Opened in 1986, this modernist building was designed by architect A.V. Shchusev, who envisioned a space to house contemporary Russian art and 20th-century masterpieces.\n\nThe New Tretyakov Gallery is distinguished by its extensive collection of modern and contemporary Russian art, including works from the early 20th century to the present. It features notable Russian artists such as Kazimir Malevich, Wassily Kandinsky, and Marc Chagall, reflecting the diverse artistic movements and styles that have emerged in Russia over the past century.\n\nThe gallery\'s design emphasizes natural light and spacious exhibition halls, creating an inviting environment for visitors to explore the evolution of Russian art. As a counterpart to the original Tretyakov Gallery, the New Tretyakov Gallery provides a comprehensive overview of Russian artistic achievements and remains a significant cultural destination for art enthusiasts and researchers.</string>
    <string name="popular">Popular place</string>


</resources>